

Amitrakshar Sanyal

Date of birth: 04/05/2001 | Nationality: Indian | Gender: Male |

(+91) 07044258067 | sanyalamitrakshar@gmail.com |

https://github.com/amitrakshar01

https://www.linkedin.com/in/amitrakshar-sanyal-a59376191/

Whatsapp Messenger: https://wa.link/xs7bg2

Bally Durgapur Samabaya Palli Prantik, Near Debangan Lodge, 711205,

Howrah, Ĭndia

About me:

Software Engineer expert in Data Structures and algorithms with expertise in programming languages like Javascript, C/C++, Java, and Python. I am a five-star coder in C, Java, and Python in HackerRank with multiple Machine Learning and IoT projects as well as some Research papers in the domain of IoT. I have mentored lots of students in the field of Open Source as well as contributed a lot to Open Source repositories.

WORK EXPERIENCE

08/11/2021 - CURRENT - Mumbai, India

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN - MUNGR

Building a Dashboard from scratch using HTML, CSS, Javascript where teachers getting hired in Ed-Tech companies can test their ability and compare with other teachers globally.

02/11/2021 - CURRENT - Remote, India

MENTOR - SCRIPT WINTER OF CODE 2.0

Open Source Mentor for more than 200 students.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

06/02/2019 - CURRENT - India

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY – Institute of Radio Physics and Electronics, University of Calcutta

www.caluniv.ac.in

PROJECTS

04/05/2021 - 04/06/2021

IOT BASED TEMPERATURE AND HUMIDITY MONITORING SYSTEM FOR HILL STATIONS

https://github.com/amitrakshar01/IoT-Implementation-of-DHT11-Temperature-and-Humidity-sensor-using-NodeMCU-and-Thingspeak

Built a Temperature and Humidity Monitoring System using NodeMCU. Wrote a Conference paper on IEEE where a model was built form the same and used specifically for tea estates and other plantations in the hill stations for accurate monitoring of essential parameters.

09/09/2021 - 12/09/2021

Portfolio Optimization

https://github.com/amitrakshar01/Portfolio-Optimization

Using classical algorithms, specifically Efficient Frontier Method to find out an overall optimized portfolio.

TECHNICAL STACK

Programming Languages

C, C++, Java, Embedded C, Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Front-end

ReactJs, AngularJs

Database

MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

IDEs

VSCode, Codeblocks, Intellij, Jupyter, Spyder, PopSQL

Back-end

Nodejs

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): **BENGALI**

Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production	Spoken interaction	
ENGLISH	C2	C2	C2	C2	C2
HINDI	C2	C2	C2	C2	C2

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Cycling

Record of 54kms on single cycling ride 4hrs)

Professional Photographer

Writer with one publication(Native language: Bengali)